export const CERAMICSA2022 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of these oxides is required to produce white glaze?",
A: "Antimony",
B: "Cobalt",
C: "Copper oxide",
D: "Tin oxide",
answer: "D. Tin oxide",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Plaster of Paris is produced by calcining",
A: "Calcium carbonate.",
B: "Gypsum.",
C: "Feldspar.",
D: "Potassium carbonate.",
answer: "B. Gypsum",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Porcelain bodies are made with",
A: "china clay.",
B: "earthenware clay.",
C: "fire clay.",
D: "stoneware clay.",
answer: "A. China clay",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. In firing, drawing refers to",
A: "designing objects.",
B: "introducing motifs.",
C: "packing wares.",
D: "removing wares.",
answer: "D. Removing wares",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A place in the Eastern region where clay can be mined is",
A: "Abetifi.",
B: "Kibi.",
C: "Akropong.",
D: "Gyakiti.",
answer: "B. Kibi",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The equipment for breaking down rocks in a ceramic studio is",
A: "blunger.",
B: "excavator.",
C: "jaw crusher.",
D: "jigger jolleying.",
answer: "C. Jaw crusher",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A traditional poticr burnishes pots with",
A: "comb,",
B: "kidney.",
C: "pebble.",
D: "spoon,",
answer: "C. Pebble",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Another name for calcium is",
A: "borax.",
B: "feldspar.",
C: "flux.",
D: "whiting.",
answer: "D. Whiting",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The tool for measuring the width of pots is",
A: "post gauge.",
B: "thermostat.",
C: "turn table.",
D: "spatula.",
answer: "A. Post gauge",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Special refractory boxes for clost firing in firewood kilns are",
A: "arches.",
B: "cranks",
C: "hovels.",
D: "sag gars",
answer: "D. Saggars",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. In what state ts a clay brittle?",
A: "Bone-drv",
B: "Bisque",
C: "Glost",
D: "Leatherhard",
answer: "A. Bone-dry",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Embossed decoration can also be termed",
A: "inlaid.",
B: "intagho,",
C: "relief,",
D: "sgraffito.",
answer: "C. Relief",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Crystals of Aluminium silicate are referred to as",
A: "mullite.",
B: "rutile.",
C: "tale.",
D: "whiting.",
answer: "A. Mullite",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The addition of coarse grog to sedimentary clay",
A: "decreases particles size.",
B: "decreases plasticity.",
C: "increases shrinkage.",
D: "increases water content.",
answer: "B. Decreases plasticity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Moulds are appropniate for",
A: "modelling variety of products.",
B: "grinding glaze materials.",
C: "producing exact copies of wares.",
D: "storing casting slip.",
answer: "C. Producing exact copies of wares",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Tall pots are best dried by placing them",
A: "in large polythene bags.",
B: "in shady areas with bottom parts covered.",
C: "on racks in a cool place.",
D: "on stripes of wood.",
answer: "B. In shady areas with bottom parts covered",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Turning is done to",
A: "facilitate drying of objects.",
B: "facilitate removal of excess clay.",
C: "give pots smooth base.",
D: "reduce shrinkage of pots.",
answer: "B. Facilitate removal of excess clay",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of these ceramic decorations is done at the glost stage?",
A: "Incising",
B: "Sgrafitto",
C: "Slip",
D: "Transfer",
answer: "D. Transfer",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following is a forming equipment?",
A: "Blunger",
B: "Kiln",
C: "Potter’s wheel",
D: "Weighing scale",
answer: "C. Potter’s wheel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Technically, firing without sufficient amount of oxygen in the kiln chamber causes",
A: "blistering.",
B: "dunting.",
C: "oxidation.",
D: "reduction.",
answer: "D. Reduction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following aids suspension in casting?",
A: "Aluminium silicate",
B: "Copper carbonate",
C: "Sodium carbonate",
D: "Sodium silicate",
answer: "D. Sodium silicate",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A clay body must be well-prepared in order to",
A: "ensure slow and even drying.",
B: "make it adequately porous.",
C: "make it sufficiently homogenous.",
D: "remove iron from it.",
answer: "C. Make it sufficiently homogenous",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. To reduce shrinkage in clay it must be",
A: "aged.",
B: "grogged.",
C: "pounded.",
D: "washed.",
answer: "B. Grogged",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. At the bone-dry state, clay contains",
A: "chemically-bonded water.",
B: "chemical water only.",
C: "distilled water.",
D: "physical water only.",
answer: "D. Physical water only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. To minimize shrinkage in thrown wares,",
A: "add bentonite to the body.",
B: "add grog to the body.",
C: "dry ware under shade.",
D: "throw ware bigger.",
answer: "B. Add grog to the body",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Fast drying of moist ware is checked by",
A: "covering them with jute sack.",
B: "placing them on sacks.",
C: "storing them in cool places.",
D: "wrapping them with polythene sheets.",
answer: "D. Wrapping them with polythene sheets",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Correcting pinholing in a glaze requires",
A: "adding flint to the glaze.",
B: "making glaze more fluid.",
C: "removing all traces of oil on the ware.",
D: "wedging properly to expel air bubbles.",
answer: "C. Removing all traces of oil on the ware",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Saggar is to firewood kiln as element is to",
A: "electric kiln.",
B: "gas kiln.",
C: "oil kiln.",
D: "saw dust kiln.",
answer: "A. Electric kiln",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. In slab construction, joints are strengthened by applying",
A: "big balls of clay.",
B: "leatherhard clay.",
C: "thick clay slip.",
D: "thin coils of clay.",
answer: "C. Thick clay slip",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of these are health hazards in a ceramic studio? \nI. Dusty studi \nII. Firing at high temperatur \nIII. Long hours in the studi \nIV. Poor ventilatio \nV. Slippery floor",
A: "I, I, IT only",
B: "I, II, IV only",
C: "II, IV, V only",
D: "I, IV, V only",
answer: "B. I, II, IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Idea development starts with",
A: "evaluation of work.",
B: "identification of problem.",
C: "investigation of problem.",
D: "visualization of a solution.",
answer: "B. Identification of problem",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of these shows that a pot is porous?",
A: "Ability to cool water",
B: "Allowing easy evaporation of water",
C: "Inability to cool water",
D: "Slow absorption of water",
answer: "B. Allowing easy evaporation of water",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following are faults in throwing?",
A: "Wobbling and running",
B: "Sagging and crawling",
C: "Running and crawling",
D: "Wobbling and sagging",
answer: "D. Wobbling and sagging",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following is the most active fluxing agent?",
A: "Borax",
B: "Feldspar",
C: "Whiting",
D: "Zinc",
answer: "A. Borax",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The simplest method for applying glaze is by",
A: "dipping.",
B: "painting.",
C: "pouring.",
D: "spraying.",
answer: "A. Dipping",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The most frequent faults in pottery production are",
A: "cracking and warping.",
B: "crazing and warping.",
C: "dunting and peeling.",
D: "sagging and cracking.",
answer: "A. Cracking and warping",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The most convenient method of producing complicated shapes is",
A: "casting.",
B: "coiling.",
C: "slabbing.",
D: "throwing.",
answer: "A. Casting",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which condition is appropriate for drying pots fast?",
A: "High humidity",
B: "High pressure",
C: "Low humidity",
D: "Low pressure",
answer: "C. Low humidity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Drying and firing are the main causes of",
A: "density.",
B: "porosity.",
C: "shrinkage.",
D: "warpage,",
answer: "C. Shrinkage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The most appropriate method of glazing the exterior of large pots is by",
A: "dipping.",
B: "painting.",
C: "pouring.",
D: "spraying.",
answer: "A. Dipping",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]